# SHVETA KUMAR 416-518-3315

Toronto, Canada sk@shveta.ca

#### **ABOUT ME**

10 years of work experience as a Business Analyst. Primarily worked as a consultant for pharmaceutical companies on project implementation. Most recent experience included working within a product development team (startup environment). Also have extensive experience with testing.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Solution Delivery Manager (Product Development) – Deloitte & Touche LLC. – Oct 2018 – March 2020 Maryland, USA & Toronto, Canada Business Analyst, Test Lead

- Worked as a Business Analyst on the product development team to build a rebate management system
- Served as the liaison between clients, project implementation teams and engineering teams to support the build and deployment of different workstreams within the software
- Participated in daily meetings with engineering teams to review wireframes and business requirements
- Participated in weekly meetings for requirements gathering, forecasting, clearing backlog tickets and user story prioritization. Used JIRA for managing tickets and user stories
- Created over 1000+ pages of user guides for the client. User guides were later used to train new hires within the company and onboarding new developers
- Provided feedback and suggestions to the Product Development Lead to streamline business processes within the team. Helped mitigate last minute rush for build deployment.
- Oversaw and managed User Acceptance Testing across the different workstreams and participated in build deployment decisions
- Prepared and led week-long trainings with clients utilizing user guides, training materials and video guides

**Sr. Consultant (Project Implementation) – Highpoint Solutions LLC. (IQVIA) — Nov 2015 – Sep 2018** Business Analyst, Test Lead – AstraZeneca, Johnson & Johnson, USA Test Analyst for Medicaid and Sales Based contracts – Glenmark Pharmaceuticals, USA Contract Analyst – DuPuy Synthes, USA

- Worked as a Business Analyst with primary focus on implementing a revenue management system.
- Gathered requirements for the pharmaceutical drug rebate programs and prepared Work Instructions, Standard Operating Procedures and Functional Requirements Documents
- Conducted demo sessions and training sessions with the client using the prepared training materials and training documents
- Using existing system functionality, developed strategies to meet client specific scenarios without the need for adding additional functionality in the system and ensured the strategy is scalable
- Verified code (formulae) created by the technical team for correctness and suggested improvements
- Created correctness models in Excel to verify that the system output is correct to ensure payment accuracy
- Trained new team members on the business processes, system functionality and the test methodology ensuring that high quality test scripts were created, and team members function with minimal supervision
- Provided additional support to other Business Analyst on the project and served as backup for additional service areas
- Conducted UAT and SIT sessions and maintained test reports and traceability matrix. Used HP ALM for testing
- Documented and maintained bugs in JIRA
- Participated in daily Scrum meetings (Agile methodology)

## Consultant - Cognizant Technology Solutions - August 2010 - May 2014

Business Analyst, Quality Assurance Analyst, Validation Analyst, Technical Writer, Project Manager – Otsuka America Pharmaceuticals, USA

- Worked as the Business Analyst for the Commercial Systems department and lead the QA team (11 members) for the New Jersey location and offshore teams in India (10 members)
- Worked directly with the client to understand the business process, documented new requirements and made updates to existing ones to ensure accuracy
- Created UML diagrams as a part of requirement gathering sessions
- Coordinated and managed offshore teams in Canada, U.K. and India ensuring timely completion of tasks
- Handled multiple projects with extremely aggressive timelines as well as maintenance requests without compromising project schedules
- Created and conducted presentations with the Project Managers and the Commercial Department VP to provide project status and discuss any project constraints
- Created Testing Life Cycle documentation such as Test Plans, Test Summary Reports and scripts.
- Reviewed existing client SOPs and templates and updated them to improve the business processes
- Ensured all documentation is compliant with FDA rules and regulations
- Served as the backup Project Manager

### Consultant - Software Catalyst LLC. - January 2008 - July 2010

Test Lead, Validation Lead, Test Script Writer - Vertex Pharmaceuticals, USA

- Worked as a Test Lead for multiple change controls on a rolling basis for deployed software
- Reviewed all requirements documentation to ensure all requirements are testable and accurate
- Ensure that all changes are documented and tested as a part of validation activities
- Manage project related testing activities for change requests and projects in different locations (San-Diego, U.K and Boston) on a regular basis
- Managed multiple projects in a Validation Lead role and developed Validation Plans, Test Plans, Test Scripts,
  Validation Summary Reports and Test Reports for multiple projects running simultaneously, and assisted multiple Team Leads with testing activities
- Reviewed and created SOP's and Work Instructions
- Attended weekly meetings to discuss project updates and issues pertaining to timelines, deliverables and requirements

### **ACADEMIC BACKGROUND**

B.E, Chemical Engineering, The City College of New York, September 2007

University of Pennsylvania, Bootcamp for Full Stack Web Development (6 months), expected completion July, 2020